## LEVY NAIBEI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Nairobi Kenya

#### PHONE

+254710311897

#### EMAIL

levynaibei2@gmail.com

#### LINKS

**LinkedIn** 

<u>Github</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>

#### SKILLS

Reactis

HTML/CSS/JS

Redux

Djangorest

Node.js

MongoDB/MySQL/PSQL

Git & Github

Firebase

#### HOBBIES

- Interacting with people of diverse backgrounds
- Playing piano
- Hiking and visiting nature trails
- Exploring about latest technologies

#### PROFILE

I am a motivated Software Engineer, with 3+ years of experience having worked remotely and onsite. I am proficient in Reactjs, Djangorest, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Vercel, Heroku, Netlify, Git/Github, GraphQl, RESTful APIs, Unit and Integration tests, Agile

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Software Engineer, Ecubeglobal Tech

India

Dec 2022 — May 2023

- · Write clean and reusable code to develop functional web applications.
- · Troubleshoot and debug applications.
- Working throughout the development life-cycle to create a seamless pipeline of work from
  - development through production.
- Keeping up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies and devising elegant
  - solutions for development optimization, in consultation with the tech leadership.
- · Gather and address technical and design requirements.

Tech-stack: Reactjs, Redux, Tailwind CSS, Djangorest, mongoDB, AWS

## Information Technology Specialist, 51 Degrees Ltd

Meru, Kenya

Dec 2020 — Nov 2022

- · Developing UI components using react sharepoint framework
- · APIs integration using Python
- · Writing Unit and Integration tests
- · Adding functionalities to existing software applications
- Integrating React App with mapbox and google APIs
- · Writing python scripts for task automation
- Administration of company web app
  Tech stack: React, Sharepoint Framework, Postgres, Docker, Python

# Software Engineering Fellow, Major League Hacking(MLH)

New York

Sep 2020 — Dec 2020

- In a remote Agile team, I built the UI for LearnForFree, an app that gets free courses from various online learning platforms such as edX, Coursera, FutureLearn and relays them to users
- built interface for AskFlow, a CLI tool that fetches answers from StackOverflow once an error occurs in your code and displays them at the terminal by querying stackExchange API. I also published the tool as pip package in PyPI
- Built, Trained and Deployed a machine learning model that predicts cancer. It classifies blood cells as either malignant or benign
- learnt new technologies such as Serverless, as I gained real-world experience and further grew my technical and professional skills and competence.

- learnt open source software engineering best practices, e.g applying the best practices in git workflow
- Participated in webinars held by engineers from Facebook, Github, Twilio etc, about the challenges they face and how i can be part of the solution

Tech Stack: AJAX, ReactJs, Python, Flask, Django

### Web Developer, Telesim Solutions

Delaware, US

Jun 2020 — Sep 2020

- Worked in remote agile team to build a platform that delivers rapid and affordable training and education to the health force in Africa during COVID19 and beyond.
- The delivery platform uses a cloud-based service-oriented platform to deliver high data content that can be accessed with or without data connection and Wi-Fi in low-resource settings

## **Technical Team Lead, Facebook Developer Circles**

Nairobi

Apr 2020 — Jul 2020

- In a remote agile team, I led a team of 6 backend and frontend engineers in designing and developing web app that can help small-scale famers boost their profit and agricultural productivity
- Designed and developed Novelty COVID-19 infections impact estimator double income and productivity of small scale farmers
- Managed project using github: creating a team, creating team repo (and access), assigned tasks(as issues and linked them to project) for automatic update of project board
- · Platform Integration: Slack github, Slack DixiApp, codacy github
- · System design: came up with user stories
- · Agile project management: product backlog, user stories, standups, sprints
- · Configured Celery to asynchronously send emails
- Ensured project requirements are adhered to: Commit message, feature branch naming and Pull Request conventions
- · Wrote clean code, debugged (with pdb, chrome dev tool)
- Worked in agile teams to build real-world, locally and relevant solutions focused on the Sustainable Development Goals(SDGs)
- · Tech stack: React, CSS3, HTML5, Django-rest-framework, Postgres

#### Software Developer, EIT Africa Ltd

Nairobi

Aug 2019 — Nov 2019

- Developed an E-policy system, Integrated USSD with M-PESA(money transfer) paybill number
- Researched and designed software programs
- Recommended software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization
- · Debugged software, evaluation and deployment

Tech-stack: Django, CSS, HTML

#### EDUCATION

## BSc Telecommunication & Information Engineering , Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Nairobi

Jan 2012 — Aug 2016

Second Class Honors (Upper Division)